# **Mohamed Soliman**

Full Stack Software Developer

405-821-5322

Oklahoma City, OK moeabraham12@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/moeabraham Website: https://moeabraham.netlify.app/

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

A software Engineer with previous experience working as an Electrical Engineer and in sales/marketing. I am always curious to learn more and to utilize my past diverse work experiences to find problem solutions and to always positively contribute to my team.

### Languages:

Front End Development: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, jQuery, Python Back- End Development: Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Django

# **Projects**

• Team Data - https://moeabraham.github.io/module-1-proj/

Using JS/HTML5/CSS3/jQuery to Allow the user to search his favorite soccer team information by making an API fetch call.

- Activity-Tracker https://activity-project-unit.herokuapp.com/
  - Using Nodejs/express/mongo dB/EJS to create a server-side to-do app for the user.
- Music Data https://musicdata.netlify.appp/

Using ReactJS/mongo DB/NodeJS/express to create a full stack music library to the user to store his favorite music data.

Soccer Cards Collector – https://soccercards.herokuapp.com/

Using Python/Django/jQuery to allow the user to create cards for his favorite Team/Players and log next features for the team.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Google UX Design Professional Certificate | Currently enrolled as a student

April 2022-Present

• Expected to graduate by October 2022.

#### **Heartland Payment Solutions | Sales Executive**

January 2018-June 2020

- Engaged new customers and strengthened existing relationships through account management.
- Initiated new business opportunities by working with other companies to drive customer acquisition through marketing initiatives and corporate events.
- Generated sales leads organically, as well as through customer referrals, Internet research, and cold calling for various accounts.

# **Corsa Nautica** in **Barcelona** | Marketing Representative Intern

June 2016 - September 2016

- Maintained social media presence on Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, and Website.
- Generated new leads by establishing and maintaining professional relationships with all clients.

#### **Orange Business Services** in **Cairo** | IT Change Management Coordinator

October 2015 - March 2016

- Coordinated between impacted servers departments to facilitate the change process
- Conformed to the agreed SLA in regard to adhering to the change management process and methodology.

Aiesec | Incoming Exchange Team coordinator

November 2012-November 2014

# **EDUCATION**

Arab Academy for Science and Technology EAE Business School General Assembly Bachelors Degree in Electrical Engineering Master's in Marketing and Sales Full stack web development, part-time

2007 - 2013 2016 - 2017 2021 Feb-Nov